Carlos Alberto Mendoza

Bogotá, Colombia · linkedin.com/in/carlos-mendoza-060097225 · +57 3169781560 · cm33673@gmail.com

My career has been a journey through different industries, each one teaching me something new and shaping who I am today. I started out as an Environmental Engineer, then I followed my passion for teaching English where I spent five years. Later,I made the leap into the customer service industry, where I sharpened my communication and problem-solving skills. Now, I'm channeling all those experiences into the tech world as a full-stack developer, where I had the opportunity to develop a learning platform for our Lingolandias Online School, as well as the landing page and the app.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lingolandias Online School

Full-Stack Developer

Bogotá, Colombia November 2023– Present

- Developing the Lingolandias Academy platform where the students and teachers meet to have their daily classes, with chat integrated and soon assignment of activities, among other features.
- Developing the landing page of our Academy, where they can test their language level by taking a test and receiving the score via email
- Working as well on the App with React Native that will be released next year.

Intouch CX

Customer Service Representative

Bogotá, Colombia October 2023– Present

- Responded to customer inquiries about Loreal via phone, chat or email.
- Provided accurate information about products, services, and company policies.
- Helped troubleshoot and resolve customer complaints in a timely manner.
- Called and provided assistance to customers who had Health Related Complaints regarding Loreal products.
- Worked with other departments to resolve customer issues effectively and participated in team meetings to share updates and best practices.

SENA - Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje

English Instructor

Valledupar, Colombia

Feb 2019 – September 2023

- Foster a positive and inclusive classroom environment.
- Created, administered, and graded assignments, quizzes, and tests.
- Tracked and reported student progress to parents, guardians, or administration.
- Use a variety of teaching methods to accommodate different learning styles (e.g., lectures, discussions, interactive activities).

Hospital Emiro Quintero Cañozares

Environmental Engineer

Ocaña, Colombia *April 2017–December 2018*

- Developed and implemented waste management systems to ensure the safe disposal of hazardous medical materials.
- Collaborated with hospital administrators to design energy-efficient systems that reduced the environmental footprint of the facility

EDUCATION

HENRY

Full-Stack Developer

Bogotá, Colombia November 2024

Ocaña, Colombia March 2017

UNIVERSIDAD FRANCISCO DE PAULA SANTANDER OCAÑA

Environmental Engineering

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Fluent English Speaker with a C1 level accredited by CEFR
- Strong written and verbal communication skills.